start with a right Isles triangle of
area one we can cut this triangle into
eight congruent right isoceles triangles
if we fill in exactly seven of those
triangles like this then we've shaded an
area of 7/8 now we can take that diagram
and scale it and put it in the last 1/8
therefore shading an extra 7/8 of 1/8 or
7 over 8^ squar if we do this again we
shade 7 over 8 cubed and then 7 over 8
4th and so on as we repeat this process
we keep shading 7/ 8 the N of the
triangle as n increases if we do this
indefinitely meaning we consider a
limiting process we eventually shade the
entire triangle therefore the Shaded
area is also one one interpretation of
this equality is that 7 repeating in
base 8 is equal to 1 another
interpretation is that 7 * the infinite
sum of the powers of 1/8 is 1 so that
the infinite sum of the powers of 1/8 is
17th